Guide to the Cormac McCarthy Papers
The Wittliff Collections
- Blood Meridian, 1980-1987, undated
  - Drafts, undated
    - Printout draft with many typescript pages. Holograph corrections in pencil. Numbered 1-452 (471 leaves). Irregular pagination, undated (Box 37, Folder 3)
      [title page]; [acknowledgments]; [quotations]; 1-124; 124a; 125-169; 169a to 169c; 170-172; 172a; 173-253; 254/255/256; 257-319; 310x to 319x; 320-352; 352a; 353-393; 394/395; 396-412; [no #]; 413a; 413-420; 420a; 421-452.
    - Box for draft in box 37, folder 3. Gray Southworth typewriter paper box. Marked "Blood Meridian - Orig. MS – Draft 2" in pencil (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Fragments, 1983, undated
    - Early draft fragments. Typescript pages with holograph corrections and clean photocopy pages. Includes a pencil rendering of a building. Non-continuous pagination. (96 leaves), undated (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Early draft fragments. Typescript pages with holograph corrections throughout. Includes some photocopy pages. Non-continuous pagination. (134 leaves), undated (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Typescript pages with holograph corrections in pencil. Pages contain two non-continuous numbering sequences. (104 leaves), undated (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Partial photocopy of fragments in box 38, folder 4. Contains occasional holograph corrections. Includes folder marked in pencil "final corrected ms – Aug 83 / (but not retyped)." (68 leaves, plus folder), August, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Photocopy of printout pages incorporating the edits in box 39, folder 1, with light holograph corrections. Non-continuously numbered 310-432. (38 leaves), undated (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Typescript pages with holograph corrections. Includes envelope fragment marked in pencil, "These are the (old pages) Retyped out of 1st 169 pp – Feb 83." Non-continuous pagination. (89 leaves, plus envelope fragment), February, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Typescript pages with holograph corrections. Includes folder fragment marked in pencil, "These are the last pp Margie Retyped." Pages contain two non-continuous numbering sequences. (109 leaves, plus folder fragment), undated (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Photocopy of corrected pages. Non-continuously numbered 312-451. No holograph corrections. (103 leaves), undated (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Partial photocopy of draft. Numbered 1-169c. Includes folder marked in blue ink, "Xeroxes of pp 1-69 B/MD." (173 leaves, plus folder), undated (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Partial photocopy numbered pp. 1-319 (no p. 222). Contains photocopies of the original corrected pages replaced with typescript pages in an earlier draft. No holograph corrections. Includes a holograph note, "XEROX as of 27 July 83 / pages missing are with typist." (320 leaves), 1983 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Typescript and photocopy pages of the epilogue, many with holograph corrections. Includes folder labeled "Blood – notes & pages." (7 leaves, plus folder), undated (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Proofs, 1985, undated
    - Setting copy. Annotated and corrected photocopy with hand-corrected pagination numbered 1-465, with front matter (471 leaves) housed in 2 parts, undated
      - Part 1 of 2 numbered 1-239, plus front matter: typescript title page, copyright page, acknowledgments, quotes, and half title page. (244 leaves). Continuous pagination (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Part 2 of 2 numbered 240-465. Continuous pagination with inserted typescript page 433a (227 leaves) (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Setting notes. (2 leaves), undated (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Page proofs with minor annotations. 337 pages (88 leaves in 11 sections), undated (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Page proofs. No corrections. Includes Haddon Craftsmen Book manufacturing transmittal form, 1-16-85. 342 pages (354 leaves), undated (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Photocopy of corrected long galley proofs, with occasional holograph corrections. (164 leaves), undated (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Partial long galley proofs; chapter heading pages, no annotations. (33 leaves), undated (Box 42)
    - Long galley proofs, marked "author's," no date or stamping. Light corrections in pencil. (170 leaves), undated (Box 43)
    - Long galley proofs, marked "Master Galleys," October 1. Moderate copyeditor's / setters notes in pencil and blue ink. (169 leaves), undated (Box 44)
    - Long galley proofs, marked "Master Pages," November 15. Light copyeditor's / setters notes in pencil and blue ink. (170 leaves), undated (Box 45)
- All the Pretty Horses, 1990-1994, undated
  Correspondence, notes, drafts, fragments, and proofs relating to McCarthy's 1992 novel, All the Pretty Horses.
  - Correspondence, 1994, undated
    - Folder labeled "ATPH Trans" containing 2 letters and 1 holograph page, undated (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Guillemette Belleteste to McCarthy. TLS, 1 page, January 12, 1994 (Box 46, Folder 1)
      Sending list of things that have posed problems with the French translation (not included).
    - Hiroshi Hayakawa to McCarthy. Photocopy, 4 pages, January 14, 1994 (Box 46, Folder 1)
      Queries from the Japanese translator. Includes McCarthy's answers to twenty-nine questions.
    - Holograph page of notes (possibly Belleteste's queries), undated (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Richard Estrada to McCarthy. TLS, 1 p. (plus 23 leaves and folder), undated (Box 46, Folder 2)
      Compliments McCarthy's Spanish and encloses pencil-corrected photocopies of typescript pages.
  - Notes, 1990-1991, 1998, undated
    - Heavily annotated manila folder, labeled "Pretty Horses," marked "old notes, history (Sep 98)," and containing typescript note pages, hand-drawn maps, photocopy maps of Saltillo and Zacatecas, and a photocopy of a 1954 J. Frank Dobie article, "Babicora," published in The American Hereford Journal. (20 leaves, plus folder), 1998, undated (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - 6 manila folders (empty) with holograph notations and corresponding page numbers, undated (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Typescript notes with holograph additions, "October 18 1991, Transcribed from small notebook notes" (2 leaves), and holograph notes with page number references (2 leaves), October 18 1991, undated (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Spanish style sheet, 2 copies. Photocopy. (10 leaves), undated (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Photocopy draft pages containing Spanish phrases with occasional pencil notation. In folder labeled, "Span – ALL pp / Sept 9 '90" (78 leaves, plus folder), 1990 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Photocopy draft pages containing Spanish phrases with occasional pencil notation. In folder labeled, "Span – ALL pp / Sept 9 '90" (78 leaves, plus folder), 1990 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Holograph title pages (2 leaves), plus photocopy of mailing list, n.d. (1 leaf), undated (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Drafts, 1991, undated
    - Typescript, first draft. Heavily corrected, 441 pp (501 leaves). Irregular pagination, undated (Box 46, Folder 9)
      1-18; 18a; 18b; 19-26; 26a; 27-42; 42a; 42b; 43-44; 44a; 45-49; 49a; 50; 50a; 51-56; 56a; 57-82; 82a; 83; 83a; 84; 84a; 85-113; 113a; 114-139; 139a; 140-143; 143a; 144; 144a; 145-149; 149a; 150-152; 152a; 153-163; 163a; 163b; 164-165; 165b; 166-170; 170a; 171-172; 172a; 173-179; 179a; 180-184; 184a; 185-186; 186a; 187/188; 189; 189a; 190-193; 193a; 194-199; 199a; 200-202; 202a; 203-211; 211a; 212; 212a; 212b; 213; 213a; 214-216; 216a; 217-225; 225a; 225b; 226; 226a; 227; 227a; 228-255; 255a; 256; 256a; 257; 257a; 258-259; 259a; 259b; 260; 260a; 261-262; 262; 263-264; 264a; 265-270; 271a; 271-274; 274a; 275-276; 276a; 277-278; 278-28-; 281/282/283; 284-291; 291a; 292-300; 300a; 301-302; 302a; 303; 303a; 304-327; 327*; 328-331; 331a; 332-348; 348*; 349-381; 381a; 382-383; 383x; 384-397; 397a; 398-410; 410a; 411-438; 438x; 439-441
    - Box for draft in box 46, folder 9. White Niftee Copies paper box. Marked "Orig. 1st Draft / All the Pretty Horses" (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Photocopy of heavily corrected early typescript draft. No corrections. 365 pages (382 leaves) housed in 2 parts, undated
      - Part 1 of 2 numbered 1-170. (183 leaves). Irregular pagination (Box 47, Folder 2)
        1-42; 42a; 43-82; 83; 83a; 84; 84a; 85-97; 97-132; 137-143; 143a; 144; 144a; 145-149; 149a; 150-153; 153a; 154-163; 163a; 163-170
      - Part 2 of 2 numbered 170a-365. (199 leaves). Irregular pagination (Box 47, Folder 3)
        170a; 171-254; 225a; 225b; 255-311; 311*; 312-365
    - Printout, "late draft." Holograph notes and corrections. Page numbers every 15 pages. (383 leaves), undated (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Box for draft in box 48, folder 1. White Gilbert paper box marked in blue ink, "Orig Mss / 3rd Draft / ATPH," and in pencil, "1st copy / unnumbered pp." (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Printout, "final draft." No corrections. 396 pages, undated (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Box for draft in box 49, folder 1. Grey Southworth paper box marked "orig mss / final draft / ATPH / no corr's." (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Photocopy of printout draft with holograph title page and several replacement typescript pages (pages 38; 93; 107; 177-178; 237; 240; 270; 274-277; 284; 289; 325-333; 333a-333c; 395-396). Heavily corrected. 396 pages (404 leaves), undated (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Box for draft in box 50, folder 1. White Niftee Copies paper box marked in blue ink, "Original mss / final draft / ATPH / w/pencil corr's." (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Photocopy of previous corrected draft, marked "revision 3/19/91." Contains additional holograph corrections and editor's queries. 396 pages (404 leaves) (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Fragments, undated
    - Typescript pages, heavily corrected. Includes some photocopy pages and 1 holograph page in manila folder labeled "APH various pages." (16 leaves, plus folder), undated (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Photocopy pages, lightly corrected. (2 leaves), undated (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Typescript pages, heavily corrected in folder labeled "APH." (21 leaves, plus folder), undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Final draft fragments. Print-out pages with holograph corrections. The draft incorporating these changes is in box 49 folder 1. (44 leaves), undated (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Typescript and photocopy pages, heavily corrected, in manila folder labeled "APH some unused pages." (142 leaves, plus folder), undated (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Photocopy pages in manila folder labeled "APH." (38 leaves, plus folder), undated (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Proofs, 1991-1992
    - Photocopy with copy editor's notes and green setters marks. 396 pages (Housed in 2 parts), undated (Box 52, Folder 1-2)
    - Photocopy p. 307 "A Note on Type," with setters marks. 1 page, undated (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - First pass proof. Stamped "Rough Pages" with copyeditors notes in red and setters marks in green. (Housed in 2 parts), November 12-13, 1991 (Box 52, Folder 4-5)
    - "Author's Galleys" with pencil corrections. Light pencil corrections. (Housed in 2 parts), November 12-13, 1991 (Box 52, Folder 6-7)
    - Second pass proof. Holograph corrections (Housed in 2 parts), January 2, 1992 (Box 53, Folder 1-2)
    - Box for second pass proof. White Niftee Copies paper box marked ""ATPH Proofs / (no orig corr's)" (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - "Master Proofs" with setters notes. (Housed in 2 parts), January 2, 1992 (Box 53, Folder 4-5)
    - Final proofs labeled, "Absolute Last Draft." (Housed in 2 parts), January 2, 1992 (Box 54, Folder 1-2)
    - Vellum proofs. (Housed in 2 parts), January 31, 1992 (Box 54, Folder 3-4)
    - Proof fragments, marked "AU correx [sic] to pages," (33 leaves), January 2, 1992 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Page proofs with no corrections, 302 pages (80 leaves in 10 sections), undated (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Adaptations by Others, 1993
    - All the Pretty Horses screenplay adaptation by Ted Tally, first draft. 158 pages. (159 leaves plus original ICM cover), September 2, 1993 (Box 54, Folder 7)
- The Crossing, 1987-1994, undated
  Correspondence, notes, drafts, fragments, proofs, and production material relating to McCarthy's 1994 novel, The Crossing.
  - Correspondence, 1993-1994
    - Amanda (Binky) Urban to McCarthy. Facsimile, 40 pages, April 14, 1993 (Box 55, Folder 1)
      Forwarding pages with "dicey transition points" in scenes depicting Billy's hunt for the wolf. In folder labeled "The Crossing."
    - Barry G. King, Jr. M.D. to McCarthy. TLS, 5 pages, November 29, 1993 (Box 55, Folder 2)
      Providing medical commentary on pages depicting Boyd's surgery in Mexico: "From a literary standpoint, there is no doubt that the scene well depicts the adversity Boyd faces in the character of the Mexican physician who intervenes. However, from a purely medical view, it doesn't tie together…." Includes 4 photocopy pages of typescript draft for review.
    - Oren H. Ellis, M.D. to McCarthy. TLS, 3 pages, December 2, 1993 (Box 55, Folder 2)
      Commenting on pages depicting Boyd's surgery in Mexico. Provides suggestions for making it more believable.
    - Barry G. King, M.D. to McCarthy. ANS, 1 page, January 11, 1994 (Box 55, Folder 2)
      Note written on an overdue notice from The University of Texas-El Paso's library asking McCarthy to return books Maria King had checked out and loaned to him.
    - Barry G. King, M.D. to McCarthy. TLS, 10 pages, April 13, 1994 (Box 55, Folder 2)
      Suggesting a few minor modifications to medical description that "could be eliminated without losing the structural integrity of the scene."
    - Barry G. King, M.D. to McCarthy. Facsimile, 1 page, March 28, 1994 (Box 55, Folder 2)
      Providing a follow-up on the period appropriateness for some of the medical instruments.
    - Barry G. King, M.D. to McCarthy. Photocopy of facsimile, 14 pages, April 13, 1994 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Barry G. King, M.D. to McCarthy. ANS, 1 page plus corrected pages. 9 leaves, undated (Box 55, Folder 2)
      Pages 382-388B of Boyd's surgery scene with note from King on first page and notes and suggestions by him throughout.
    - Barry G. King, M.D. to McCarthy, written on a prescription sheet. ANS, 1 page, undated (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Notes, undated
    - Holograph notes with medical terminology and description. 5 leaves, undated (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Print out pages 382-388 of Boyd's surgery. 9 leaves, undated (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Folder labeled in blue, "The Crossing – Boyd's S----, dr…" Contains typescript, photocopy, and holograph pages of medical scenes with annotations by consulting doctors and McCarthy. 63 leaves, undated (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Notes regarding the priest at Caborca: Outline of his monologue. 2 leaves plus manila folder, undated (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Style sheet, photocopy. 6 leaves, undated (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Drafts, 1987-1992, undated
    - Typescript, early draft beginning dates October 1987. Heavily corrected, 389 pages (498 leaves). Irregular pagination (Box 55, Folder 6)
      [4 no #]; 1-48; 51-52; 48-55; 58; 56-57; 59-61; 58-70; 74; 71-85; 113; 113; 86-97; 133; 98-100; 136; 136; 101-107; 109; 110; 110a; 111-118; 157; 119-124a; 124-131; 131; 131-144; 144a; 145; 145a; 146-150; 150a; 188-189; 151;190; 152; [no #]; 193; 153; [no #]; 154-157; 198-200a; 202; 158-160; 203; 161-163; 207-208; 164; 208; 208; 182-185; 187; 189-199; 194; 200-201; 197; 202; 198; 203-208; 204; 209; 211; [no #]; 188; 205; 209; 204; 204; [no #]; 205; 186; [no #]; 205; 205; [no #]; 165; 210; 164; 166-168; 168a; 209; 169a; 169-177; 180; 187-190; 181; 181a; 182-183; 186; 191; 191x; 225; 192-206; 206a; 207-210; 241; 211-224; 224a; 224b; 225; 252-253; 226-237; 262; 238-243; 273; 266-276; 244-246; 280; 246a; [2 no#]; 247-249; [no #]; 250-257; [no #]; 258-260; 289; 261-267; [no #]; 269-272; 272a; 272b; 272b; 272c; 273; 272a; 273aa; 273b; 273bb; 275cc; 275cc; 268; 297; 268; 305; 271x; 274; 274; 275(1); 275(2); 275; 306; 275(3); 275(4); [no #]; 319-321; 275(5); 275(6); 275(7); 275(8); 275(9); 275(10); [2 no #]; 275(13); 275(14); 275(15); W-4b; 275(16); 275(17); 275(18); 275(21); 275(22); 275(23); 275(24); 275(25); 275(27); 275(26); 1-13; 13a; 14&15; 16-45; 385; 46-47; 386ish; 389.
    - Photocopy of corrected early draft typescript pages, no holograph corrections. 516 leaves. (Housed in 2 parts), undated
      - Part 1 of 2. Irregular reverse pagination, 250 leaves (Box 55, Folder 7)
      - Part 2 of 2. Irregular reverse pagination, 266 leaves (Box 56, Folder 1)
      - Box for draft in box 55, folder 7 and box 56, folder 1. White Stenocraft box (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Photocopy of corrected early draft typescript pages, no holograph corrections. 354 leaves. (Housed in 2 parts), undated
      - Part 1 of 2. Irregular pagination, 200 leaves (Box 56, Folder 3)
      - Part 2 of 2. Irregular pagination, 154 leaves. (Box 56, Folder 4)
      - Box for draft in box 56, folders 3-4. White Sears bond typewriter box (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Typescript, first draft. Heavily corrected, 596 pages (619 leaves). Irregular pagination, circa 1991 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      1-21; 20; 22-27; 27x; 28-50; 51a-51d; 58; 58; 51f-51h; w::; 51i-51j; 51-68; 82; 69-79; 92; 80-81; 96; 00; 96; 82-83; 97; 84; 98; 85-94; 105; 95-96; 108; 97-100; 113; 101-104; 104a; 105-115x; 115-131; 139; 139a; 132-146; 152; 152a; 147-152; 156; 153-160; 164; 161-164; 169; 165; 170; 170; 166; 168-171; 175; 172-173; 175; 173-180a; 180-195a; 195-208; 179; 217; 216; 209-248; 252-292; 290; 293-294; 293; 295-297; 295; 298-302; 300; 303-335; 348-385; 387; 386-391a; 392-394; 377-378; 378-379; 395-408; 408x; 409-413; 415; 400; 417; 414; 416; 418-444; 446a; 446; 445; 447-465; 491-499; 501-523; 470; 524-533; 480; 534-535; 480; 536-537; 483; 538; 539a-539b; 539-549; 497a; 550-570; 518aa; 518a; 519; 518a; 571-578; [45-51]; 579-596.
    - Box for draft in box 57, folder 2. Plain white typing paper box with writing on bottom edge, "1st draft – not rewritten, Jan 15 91." (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Photocopy of corrected first draft typescript. Contains some unique pages and includes only some of the changes found in previous draft 597 pp (612 leaves). Irregular pagination. (Housed in 2 parts), undated
      - Part 1 of 2 numbered 1-w***. (393 leaves). Irregular pagination (Box 58, Folder 2)
        1-27; 27x; 28-82; [no #]; 83-104; 104a; 105-115x; 115-169; [no #]; 170-180; 180a; 181-189; 182-195; 195a; 196-311; 311-319; [no #]; 320-329; [2 no #]; 330-375; w*; w**; w***
      - Part 2 of 2 numbered 376-596 (219 leaves). Irregular pagination (Box 58, Folder 3)
        376-391; [no #]; 391a; 392-408x; 408; 410; 410-437; [no #]; 438-444; 446a; 445-467; 490-538; 539a; 539b; 539-570+; 570-575; 565-579; [45-51]; 580-596.
    - Typescript with some photocopy pages, second draft. Heavily corrected, 564 pages (622 leaves). Irregular pagination, circa 1992 (Box 59, Folder 1)
      1-4; 4a; 5-27; 27a; 28-30; 30a; 31-34; 34a; 35-46; 46a; 47-48; 48a; 49-58; 58a; 59-61; 61a; 62-95; 95a; 96-98; 98a; 99-105; 105a; 106-145; 145a; 146; 146a; 147-150; 150a; 151; 151a; 152; 152a; 153-158; 158a; 159-161; 161a; 162; 162a; 163-171; 171a; 172-197; 197a; 198-206; 206a; 207-211 (insert); 211-214; 214a; 215-229; 229a; 230-231; 231a; 231b; 232-265; 265a; 266; 266a; 267-270; 270a; 271-272; 272a; 273-281; 281a; 282-296; 296a; 297-327; 327a; 328-384; 382-383; 383a; 384-386; 386-388; 388a; 388b; 388b; 382a; 383-399x; 399-400; 400a; 400-413; 413a; 414-416; 416a-416c; 417-418; 418a; 419-447; 447a; 448-450; 450a-450i; 451-452; 452a-452c; 453-461; 461a; 462-464; 464a; 465-481; 454; 482-494; 494a; 495-501; 501a; 502-506; 506a; 507-508; 508a; 509-512; 512(insert); 513-515; 515a; 516-536; 536a; 537; 537-543; 543a; 544; 544-546; 546a; 547a; 547-564.
    - Printout, with editor's [Gary Fisketjon] queries in green, 556 pages (551 leaves). (Housed in 2 parts), undated
      - Part 1 of 2 numbered 1-162; 174-289 (279 leaves (Box 59, Folder 2)
      - Part 2 of 2 numbered 285-556 (272 leaves) (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Photocopy of printout, with editor's corrections in red, 561 pages (551 leaves). (Housed in 2 parts), undated
      - Part 1 of 2 numbered 1-162; 174-289 (279 leaves) (Box 60, Folder 2)
      - Part 2 of 2 numbered 290-561 (272 leaves) (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Printout of final draft, moderately corrected in pencil. 528 pages (531 leaves). (Housed in 2 parts), undated
      - Part 1 of 2 numbered 1-268. (268 leaves) (Box 60, Folder 4)
      - Part 2 of 2 numbered 269-528 pages. Includes inserted photocopy pages 388a and 388b, and typescript insert 433x (263 leaves) (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Fragments, undated
    - Typescript pages from early draft, heavily corrected. Paginated continuously but in various sections, (188 leaves), undated (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Typescript pages, heavily corrected, numbered 296-549 (131 leaves), undated (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Typescript pages, moderately corrected. (20 leaves), undated (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Typescript pages, "Sheets removed & replaced / Spanish edits / per CMC." (29 leaves), undated (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Printout pages from late draft, heavily corrected. Numbered 1-41 (43 leaves), undated (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Printout pages, no corrections. Includes partial manila folder with holograph notes and page references. Numbered 383-413 (31 leaves), undated (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Printout pages of final draft with holograph corrections. Numbered 1-162, undated (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Printout pages of final draft incorporating changes from above draft with very few holograph corrections. Numbered 1-162, undated (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Proofs, 1994
    - Setting copy, holograph corrections, Includes internal notes regarding corrections. 512 pages, circa March 1994 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - "Rough page" proofs, moderate corrections. 421 pages (438 leaves). (Housed in 2 parts), March 21, 1994
      - Part 1 of 2 numbered 3-212 plus front matter (220 leaves) (Box 62, Folder 2)
      - Part 2 of 2 numbered 213-421. Includes twelve inserted printout pages between p. 303 and 306. (218 leaves) (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - First pass proofs, stamped in red, "Master Copy," moderate corrections. 421 pages with twelve inserted printout pages after p. 310 and with photocopy typescript fragment taped to the top of p. 409, March 21, 1994 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Incomplete lightly corrected proofs, dated March 21, 1994, with April 22, 1994 internal Knopf memo re corrections (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Photocopy proofs with minor holograph corrections. 425 pages (436 leaves). (Housed in 2 parts), April 10-11, 1994
      - Part 1 of 2 numbered 3-210 plus front matter (220 leaves) (Box 63, Folder 3)
      - Part 2 of 2 numbered 211-425 (216 leaves) (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Photocopy proofs with minor holograph corrections. 425 pages (436 leaves). Note on first page, "all logged onto revised pages note sheet." (Housed in 2 parts), April 10-11, 1994
      - Part 1 of 2 numbered 3-210 plus front matter (220 leaves) (Box 64, Folder 2)
      - Part 2 of 2 numbered 211-425 (216 leaves) (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Second pass proofs with minor holograph corrections. 425 pages (432 leaves). (Housed in 2 parts), April 10-11, 1994
      - Part 1 of 2 numbered 3-273 plus front matter (279 leaves) (Box 64, Folder 4)
      - Part 2 of 2 numbered 274-425 (153 leaves) (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Proof fragment. Various photocopy corrected typescript pages. Includes a post-it note to McCarthy. 108 leaves, April 10-11, 1994 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - "Final corrected proofs," with minor holograph corrections in green. 426 pages (430 leaves). (Housed in 2 parts), April 18, 1994
      - Part 1 of 2 numbered 3-206 plus front matter (209 leaves) (Box 65, Folder 2)
      - Part 2 of 2 numbered 207-426 (221 leaves) (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Production Materials, undated
    - Book jacket proof, Picador (Box 65, Folder 4)
- The Stonemason, a play, 1985-1999, undated
  Correspondence, notes, drafts, fragments, and proofs relating to McCarthy's play, The Stonemason. Originally started in the 1970s, it was eventually published by Ecco Press in 1994.